<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Luke Alex Davis</title><description>The website of Luke Alex Davis.</description><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/</link><item><title>Mlog #003</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/mlog/mlog-13-11-2023/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/mlog/mlog-13-11-2023/</guid><description>My mlog for this week featuring </description><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Here is my media log (mlog) for this past week (6th Nov-12th Nov)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched 10 movies this week, heavily inspired by my favourite film critic, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@TheArmchairAuteur&quot;&gt;Dom Griffin&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can check &lt;a href=&quot;https://letterboxd.com/lukealexdavis/films/diary/for/2023/11/&quot;&gt;my Letterboxd diary on their main site&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;/letterboxd-diaries/&quot;&gt;my historical diaries on my site&lt;/a&gt; but here&apos;s a quick list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Verdict&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Guilty as Sin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thick as Thieves&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nemesis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Swordfish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Face/Off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Postmortem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A Story&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sport Goofy in Soccermania&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Animalympics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of all of them, Nemesis was my favourite (a recommendation by Dom). It was directed by Albert Pyun and stars a cyborg trying to free himself from the life as a cop and the police demanding he do one last job. It&apos;s chaotic, a mess, and absolutely fantastic. At first, I was like &quot;okay, this isn&apos;t too bad&quot; and then there were two scenes that elevated my enjoyment. One involved an old woman getting harassed by a robot, only for her to pull out a gun from her bag and shooting it to death. Damn, granny! Then there was a fight scene with the main character sliding down a muddy chute and fending off a robot and it was incredible. I&apos;m very tempted to watch it all again. The plot itself is lacking and the dialogue is objectively awful but that all adds to the film&apos;s charm and I don&apos;t think Pyun was trying to make an Oscar winner here. Instead, he won my heart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contrast, my least favourite was another Pyun movie called Postmortem. It started Charlie Sheen in the lead role and it just felt like a feature length episode of Taggart (IYKYK), both for the subject matter and the fact it was set in Glasgow (it was originally meant to be set in San Francisco; talk about a switch up!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also watched Animalympics for the first time in about 25 years and that was really cool and funny. I still knew the words to the songs (thanks, brain!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon Platinum&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my playthrough a few months ago and I finally finished it. I didn&apos;t enjoy it as much as I wanted. It cemented my opinion that the original Sinnoh games were vastly overrated and I wish Gen 8 hadn&apos;t been dominated by them so much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon White&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After finishing Platinum, I had the choice of BW or XY. In the end, I chose White despite having completed Black and Black 2 already this year but I needed to give the generation one last chance to see if the first games were really that bad. The difference here is that I&apos;m playing White on an emulator and the graphics are so much better. I might actually enjoy the game this time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;yr fave film critic&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My friend Dom has a podcast series called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLLCowZunJhB7zyFfFupbXsRrhA4a6-k4G&quot;&gt;yr fave film critic&lt;/a&gt; where he talks about film news, what he&apos;s watched, and answers viewer/listener questions. It&apos;s so good and enjoyable and he has some great recommendations as well (Nemesis being one of them.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Law &amp;amp; Order clips&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I watched one a few days ago and then YouTube said &quot;here, have some more&quot; and I watched some more! I used to enjoy the show until it got so dark that it wasn&apos;t conducive to good mental health. But the clips were good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robert Palmer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowhere near as much as the weeks before but I still listened to Addicted to Love, I Didn&apos;t Mean To Turn You On, and You Are In My System amongst others&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Corinne Bailey Rae&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another amazing artist from West Yorkshire, Corinne Bailey Rae&apos;s new album Black Rainbows is amazing. It has some rock, some punk, R&amp;amp;B, electronica, classical, all of it. And her voice sounds sublime. Amazing range, you should definitely check it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other music you should check out&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eddie Chacon - Sundown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quantic - Dancing While Falling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Halibab Matador - Souvenirs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;thxk_u - B.O.B&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;earfluvv &amp;amp; aroma - Sonic Oddities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No books again this week. Still bad, I know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Mlog #002</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/mlog/mlog-5-11-2023/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/mlog/mlog-5-11-2023/</guid><description>My mlog for this week featuring </description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Nov 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Here is my media log (mlog) for this past week (31st Oct–5th Nov)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No movies this week. I tried to &quot;acquire&quot; Training Day but my &quot;means of acquisition&quot; were thwarted by slow &quot;acquitision speeds&quot; (please read between the lines here). It&apos;s on my list though!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon Crystal Legacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally completed it and I&apos;ll be doing a writeup on my Pokémon fan site, &lt;a href=&quot;https://centiskor.ch/&quot;&gt;centiskor.ch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Virtua Tennis 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still playing this on and off but it&apos;s started to freeze a lot which messes up my Career mode progress. I suppose this device wasn&apos;t really made for Dreamcast so I&apos;ll take what I can get.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Octopath Traveler 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally started it and I&apos;m enjoying it so far. The cut scenes are a bit arduous but the battle system is really cool and I&apos;ve missed buying equipment for characters. The Golden Sun inspiration is clear!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Final Fantasy Tactics Advance&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s been about 18 years since I last played this and I&apos;ve not got far yet but it&apos;s been fun to see one of my favourite GBA games in all its isometric glory. Also, the dialogue goes hard! No cutesy stuff here and I love it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robert Palmer videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m still going through my Robert Palmer hyperfixation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Astro tutorials&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site is built with Astro but I&apos;d like to improve my knowledge with JS in particular. Shout out to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@CodinginPublic&quot;&gt;Coding in Public&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rival Locke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m onto the second season of Rival Locke where they play Gold/Silver. Lots more noises and silliness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robert Palmer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no signs of stopping. Nearly at 200 scrobbles in the last month. He&apos;s was just so good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Elaquent&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really enjoyed his latest album, &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/album/5P7jvvJmgoYxcgNFY43bZc?si=q3ZOmidWQkekee60hfvXfA&quot;&gt;Rediscovery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No books read this week. Bad, I know.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Mlog #001</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/mlog/mlog-31-10-2023/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/mlog/mlog-31-10-2023/</guid><description>My mlog for Halloween 2023</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Movies&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon: The First Movie - Mewtwo Strikes Back&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A classic. No notes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon: The Movie 2000&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less of a classic but I love Lugia and the legendary Kanto birds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Coyote Ugly&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed it for what it was and it&apos;s one of my girlfriend&apos;s favourite movies so we watched it together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Deep Blue Sea&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really fun action movie from the 90s and it&apos;s another of my girlfriend&apos;s favourite movies so we watched it together for her birthday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Games&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Pokémon Crystal Legacy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really enjoying this ROM hack. Crystal is arguably the best Gen 2 game so to get an enhanced version makes it even better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Virtua Tennis 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I have a RGB30, I can play Dreamcast games easier and that means playing my favourite tennis game of all time (sorry, Mario Tennis). So fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tetris 64&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed a Tetris fix and while this version isn&apos;t the best, it did its job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Octopath Traveler 2&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&apos;t started it yet but I bought it while on offer and I&apos;m excited, although I do have &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/patientgamers/comments/9wrpey/anxiety_about_starting_a_new_game/&quot;&gt;new game anxiety&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Videos&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robert Palmer videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m currently going through a Robert Palmer obsessive phase. He was so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;George Michael videos&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m also going through another George Michael obsessive phase (I&apos;ve had a few since the late 90s). Again, so good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Rival Locke&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I needed something to listen and laugh to. If you don&apos;t know what a Rival Locke is, you should &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLAzDHex22XQypi_vE9biMsYXx4eENtINe&quot;&gt;watch the one I watched&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;People making burgers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I love burgers and I love seeing people make smash burgers. I hope I can get one of those iron press thingies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Robert Palmer&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/mlog/mlog-31-10-2023/#robert-palmer-videos&quot;&gt;See above&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Ahwlee&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Always on heavy rotation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Wun Two&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Zero 7&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See above.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Books&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bits of &lt;a href=&quot;https://uk.bookshop.org/a/3710/9781472241344&quot;&gt;Football Cliches&lt;/a&gt; (affiliate link)&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>