<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>The release notes of Luke Alex Davis</title><description>My RSS feed of release notes, where I get some things off my chest.</description><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/</link><item><title>Release Notes #15</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-15/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-15/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We&apos;re closer in time to what is known as the &quot;Trans-Atlantic Slave Trade&quot; of the 1700s–1900s or the Civil Rights Movement of the mid-20th century than the dinosaurs but look at the difference in tone when people say &quot;that was such a long time ago&quot; for both.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #14</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-14/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-14/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve not read the whole &quot;pause AI&quot; letter and I&apos;m skeptical of Elon Musk&apos;s involvement in it (I don&apos;t think it should be completely ignored or that it&apos;s mutually exclusive to the principles of the letter) but I also don&apos;t think that the polar opposite is better, ie. investors and AI tycoons saying we should accelerate instead and add safeguards in place . Like wtf? Mostly women, particularly women of colour have been shouting about these harms for years and been ignored or straight up fired (with the classic excuse of &quot;their work was below par&quot;) so if it was disregarded then, what makes them think it&apos;ll suddenly be taken seriously and competently put in place now? And who is gonna do it and check it when all the ethics teams are getting gutted? It&apos;s all a front to look like they care and that&apos;s enough for some people; no action, just a sense of awareness. Reminds me of the Defund The Police calls and Biden saying &quot;no, we should actually boost the police&apos;s budgets&quot;. UGH! /rantover&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #13</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-13/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-13/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m tired of watching movies on Amazon Prime Video and there not being any subtitles available. And these aren&apos;t obscure movies - I&apos;m talking films with famous actors in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But that shouldn&apos;t matter because all films should have subtitles available: for disabled people, neurodivergent people, people who don&apos;t understand the language the film&apos;s in, and all the various intersections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or people like me who can&apos;t stand actors mumbling their lines (or might be in the kitchen making dinner while the film&apos;s on).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I&apos;m at the bottom of the priority list.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #12</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-12/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-12/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I think it&apos;s dangerous for creatives of influence to tell other creatives that they need to follow a similar path that they did in order to be &quot;successful&quot;. It suggests that the system works linearly and any deviation is going to fail, rather than dismantle processes that otherwise oppress or restrict creativity and longevity. &quot;The system is fine, you&apos;ve just got to follow it to be like me and my peers.&quot; Bullshit. Subversion is the way to go. That&apos;s why I don&apos;t really go for reforms as a silver bullet for oppression in society. If a house is built to keep rich white folks warm and kill anyone who isn&apos;t, redecorating a few rooms won&apos;t do anything; that house has to come down. The sooner we start organising to make those moves, the better it&apos;ll be for the marginalised. And within that, we can also find our moments of joy, wonder, and happiness because there&apos;s always space for that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #11</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-11/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-11/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I&apos;ve read a fair number of articles promoting large language models and the claims are either unsubstantiated or promising a &quot;better&quot; future that can&apos;t be guaranteed. The technology and the models have been around for so long, why is there such an indefinite wait?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that time, you could just hire a subject matter expert, do the research yourself based on the existing information out there, or scale down rather than scale up on the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yes, I&apos;m a broken record because I&apos;ve spoken on this many times and yes, there are SOME positive use cases for these LLMs but they don&apos;t outweigh the nonsensical and/or harmful ones and they certainly can&apos;t make all these lofty dreams come true.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, mental health care is abysmal. Is AI the answer or a significant change in our system (by change, I really mean dismantle and restart because reform won&apos;t work IMO). Waiting lists won&apos;t be cut down because AI assisted a professional in making a questionable diagnosis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical science is biased. Where is the AI getting the data from? Who&apos;s cleaning that up? Who&apos;s testing it to ensure safety for Black patients (as one demographic example)? Who is asking these questions and who is listening and taking them onboard? What safeguards are in place?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t even get me started on AI use in the justice system!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this boils down to two things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m tired of &quot;hey, I know you said there are fundamental issues here but I think we should ignore them and feed biased data into our technology to fix it.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m tired of this era of &quot;whatever it takes to win, that&apos;s what I&apos;m saying&quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #10</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-10/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-10/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Why is everything about growth, (capitalist-led) success, and ambition? What scares us so much about the present that we hyperfocus on these ideologies?&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #9</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-9/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-9/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;What if, instead of lacking confidence, you just lack knowledge of a situation and how to handle it? What if, instead of telling people &quot;you can do it&quot;, we gave people the tools and resources they needed?&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #8</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-8/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-8/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;After 2 years of a horrific pandemic (still going btw), I&apos;d hoped-but not necessarily expected- that we&apos;d have learnt more about ourselves, how to be compassionate, and organise against oppressors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But all I see is calls to work HARDER and people doubling down on being shitty. And if you call it out? You&apos;re the inconsiderate one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rest? Wasted time. You should be finding a hustle to make passive income. Fight &apos;cancel culture&apos;, fight &apos;woke culture&apos;. Instagram infographics with 5 word quips. Nonsense, fear, and greed. Manufactured moral panic. No critical thinking, just bad vibes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s sad and a damn shame.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #7</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-7/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-7/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Today, I was asked if I could do a thing. I &lt;em&gt;nearly&lt;/em&gt; said no but I decided I&apos;d give it a try. I did better than I initially thought. The relief and joy it gave me was incredible. That&apos;s the power of Doing That Thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think there are times when you could or should defer, either to someone else or until you&apos;re ready to do it yourself, but there are times to just go do it and in spite of myself and how I&apos;ve been feeling lately, I&apos;m proud of what I did today.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #6</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-6/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-6/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;We&apos;re all on a ball of rock, grass, water, with fire in the middle like some kind of elemental chimera (or a cheat &lt;a href=&quot;/wiki/pokemon/&quot;&gt;Pokémon&lt;/a&gt;). It&apos;s &lt;strong&gt;much&lt;/strong&gt; smaller than a subatomic particle in proportion to the rest of the universe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we&apos;re lucky, we might get to live near to a century. But we (might) only get to do it once (unless you believe in reincarnation). With all that in mind, we&apos;re unfathomably small in an unfathomably large space of existence and we only have a finite time in it. So why wouldn&apos;t or shouldn&apos;t we have ideal lives and make it so that everyone else does? Why do we commend people who make life so unfathomably hard for others that they no longer want to be alive because of it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All is not well.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #5</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-5/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-5/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I see so many pithy quotes and slogans on social media, giving us directives to better life and while I agree with some and I&apos;ve promoted them as such, I wonder: where is the space for variability, fluctuation, and, in essence, humanity?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discipline is key but what happens when external forces break that discipline? There&apos;s a space between the break and returning to routine (if we even do) and it&apos;s such a crucial time. Groups like the cult of positivity and The Church of Latter Day Risers &amp;amp; Grinders say to get back in immediately and to never let a setback or negativity stop you. But that negativity could be a life lesson because there&apos;s no escaping it. How can we learn to protect ourselves or build necessary resilience if we never know what we&apos;re facing. Another problem is not having the time to do it because we&apos;ve got to survive. Many people aren&apos;t. I appreciate that. If anything, that&apos;s where space and grace needs to be given to those people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you might not get to that point if we live off the short and snappy slogans on Instagram and Twitter. It&apos;s the epitome of &quot;easier said than done&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #4</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-4/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-4/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 20 Mar 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was thinking about search, both as a technology and a human activity, and how well Google (or any company with a search engine but primarily them) and SEOs explain it to the public and understand it themselves. How much do we engage with people who search? Do we know their pain points? Why they decide to go to Twitter to ask questions instead of a search engine? Why they might ask someone else to effectively search on their behalf? I know there are videos about &quot;how search works&quot; but is that how THEY see search or is that based more on field research? Do SEOs obfuscate search to retain authority and make profit out of people instead of educating them? Are we constantly following outdated practices because we don&apos;t want to find out we&apos;re behind and need to improve? Are we selling lies and feeding biases because &quot;that&apos;s how it&apos;s always been done and it doesn&apos;t harm me!&quot;? Just some of the questions that revolve in my head that I have no time to resolve. And then I think about the mis/disinformation around search and how search engines work and instead of those companies looking inward, they go on the defensive. Who is that helping? I don&apos;t expect a masked magician search engineer to start revealing pieces of various search algorithms, presented by Mitch Pileggi. But I&apos;d prefer if the responses weren&apos;t rude and snarky or sanitised to look like there aren&apos;t biases behind the scenes when there are.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #3</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-3/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-3/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I spent too much time on Instagram. I don&apos;t post anything on my grid (in fact, I removed everything a while back) but I browse and post stories. The most common stories I see are infographics related to life and mental health. Some of them are tweets from people who may or may not have good intentions with what they say but, for me at least, I don&apos;t find them helpful at all and they reinforce the reasons why I don&apos;t talk to people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social media has provided a platform for simultaneous change and stagnation. Thanks to woeful inadequacy in public health care in the West, social media &quot;therapists&quot; have been the only source of relief for many. That&apos;s an indictment on governments and not those who genuinely try to help. But a lot of what I see skip the compassion that we need to get through difficult situations and goes straight for the jugular. We&apos;re somewhat hampered by 280 characters per tweet without turning thoughts into threads which are equally as oppressive to nuance. But the result is condensing the time and grace to navigate our feelings and emotions and spitting out two sentences that sound sharp and cut deep. That might work for some but it doesn&apos;t jostle me into action. It makes me feel like what I&apos;ve been feeling for years was a waste of time. No time to unpack it, I&apos;ve just got to... stop doing that thing. Telling me I&apos;m worth it without examining why I never thought I was puts a blanket over the burden without releasing it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&apos;ve got to dismantle the infographic industrial complex.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #2</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I know things about myself like my values and my strengths, what I like and dislike but I couldn&apos;t tell you what kind of personality I have if I even have one or whether I&apos;m just a chameleon copying everyone else&apos;s. I&apos;m amongst people and never truly feel like I fit in or that I can relate to most people. And that sucks.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title>Release Notes #1</title><link>https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-1/</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://lukealexdavis.co.uk/posts/release-notes-1/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I don&apos;t like Novak Djokovic. The dislike was petty at first but after his comments about &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2016/mar/21/novak-djokovic-indian-wells-equal-prize-money-tennis&quot;&amp;gt;women&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.rollingstone.com/culture/culture-news/novak-djokovic-anti-vaccine-987003/&quot;&amp;gt;vaccinations&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, his annoying heel turns during matches when the crowd doesn&apos;t cheer for him, and those cringey &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/atptour/status/1298084307659943937&quot;&amp;gt;rib donation celebrations&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;, I feel vindicated. I&apos;m also not pleased that he&apos;ll have the most grand slams at the end of his career. If Nadal had it, I wouldn&apos;t feel as bad (although his comments about &amp;lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sbnation.com/tennis/2018/6/13/17459962/rafael-nadal-equal-pay-tennis-male-models&quot;&amp;gt;women&apos;s prize money&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt; are equally as bad) but &amp;lt;em&amp;gt;ugh&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>